Guide to the Rochambeau Papers and Rochambeau Family Cartographic Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Map Collection of the Comte de Rochambeau, 1695-1792; Series V; 5.25; (13 boxes)
  - PLAN TO INVADE ENGLAND
    - IK 323 The British Isles. Paris: Lattré., 1769 (Box 10, Folder 357)
      Title and/or other information taken from map: LES ISLES BRITANNIQUES/ Comprenant les Royaumes/D'ANGLETERRE D'ECOSSE ET D'IRLANDE/DIVISÉS EN GRANDES PROVINCES/Subdivisés par Comtés/Dressés sur les Observations Astronomique,/Par le Sr. Janvier Geographe./A PARIS/Chés Lattré Graveur rue S. Jacques au coin de celle de la Parcheminerie à la Ville de Bordeaux./Avec Privilege du Roy. 1769. [and] Choffard. fecit.
      Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 19 7/8 x 27 3/8 inches, overall. 7 x 4 1/2 inches, folded. There is a copy of this map dated 1791 - see IK 408, also colored.
    - IK 337 Ireland. J. Rocque. (Box 10, Folder 358-361)
      1) Map tab inscription on part 1 illegible
      Inscribed on map, part 1: IK/337. [and] irlande/1
      Notes: This is the upper right quarter of the map. Linen- backed. Uncolored. 24 15/16 x 19 7/16 inches, overall. 6 1/4 x 6 5/8 inches, folded.
      2) Map tab inscription on part 2 illegible
      Inscribed on map, part 2: irlande/2
      Title and/or other information taken from map, part 2: A MAP OF THE/Kingdom of Ireland, Divided into/Provinces Counties and Baronies, shewing/The Archbishopricks, Bishopricks, Cities, Boroughs, Market Towns,/Villages, Barracks, Mountains, Lakes, Bogs, Rivers, Bridges, / Ferries, Passes; Also the Great, the Branch, & the By Post/ Roads, together with the Inland Navigation &c by J: ROCQUE/ Chorographer to HIS MAJESTY.
      Notes: This is the upper left quarter of the map. Linen- backed. Uncolored. 25 3/16 x 21 inches, overall. 6 1/4 x 7 inches, folded.
      3) Map tab inscription on part 3 illegible
      Inscribed on map, part 3: irlande/3.
      Title and/or other information taken from map, part 3: London Printed for Robt. Sayer op [continues on next page]
      Notes: This is the lower left quarter of the map. Linen- backed. Uncolored. 25 7/16 x 21 3/16 inches, overall. 6 1/4 x 7 1/4 inches, folded.
      4) Map tab inscription on part 4 illegible
      Inscribed on map, part 4: irlande/4
      Title and/or other information taken from map, part 4: [continued from previous part] posite Fetter Lane Fleet Street.
      Notes: This is the lower right quarter of the map. Linen- backed. Uncolored. 25 15/16 x 20 inches, overall. 6 5/8 x 6 3/4 inches, folded.
    - IK 322 The Provinces of the Low Countries. Paris: Eugene Henry Friex., 1744
      Map tab inscription: 1744/Côtes d'Angleterre/IK/322.
      Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTES/DES PROVINCES DES/PAYS BAS/Contenant/les Comtés de Flandre, de Hainaut,/de Cambresis, le Duché de Brabant,/partie des Duchés de Luxembourg,/de Limbourg, de Julliers l'Evêché de/ Liege, Boulenois et frontiere de Picardie/DRESSÉE/Sur les Memoires de Eugene Henry Friex et augmente/sur les Observations les plus nouvelles,/Ces Cartes si exactes et si detaillées sont tres/necessaires pour Campements et Marches des Armées/elles sont toutes sur une même echelle/ et peuvent s'assembler en/une même Carte/1744./A PARIS/Chez Crepy rue S. Jacques/pres la rue de la Parchemine/rie à S. Pierre. [and] PARTIE DES COTES DE L'ANGLETERRE./en 1744. [and] Dressé Sur les Memoires de Eugene henry Friex. a Paris Chez Crepy rue S. Jacques a limage S. Pierre.
      Notes: Uncolored. 23 1/4 X 31 1/4 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 873.
    - IK 331bis Coasts of Ireland and England. (Box 11, Folder 362)
      Map tab inscription: Carte des cotes/d'Irlande et/des cotes offiden (?)/cotes de l'angleterre
      Inscribed on map: IK 331 bis
      Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE GENERALE/des Costes/D'IRLANDE,/et des Costes Occidentales/ D'ANGLETERRE/avec une Partie de celles/D'ECOSSE/Prix trente Sols H: van Loon Sculp:
      Notes: Linen-backed. Uncolored. 25 1/4 x 36 1/2 inches, overall. 6 1/2 x 4 3/4 inches folded.
    - IK 332 Maritime Chart of the Coasts of Western Europe. Le Havre: Dicquemare., 1772 (Box 11, Folder 363)
      Inscribed on map: carte marine/de la manche/et du golphe/ de biscaye. [and] IK/332.
      Title and/or other information taken from map: LE/PONANT/ PAR M. L'ABBÉ DICQUEMARE/De plusieurs Académies Prof. de Phys. Ex. &c./AU HAVRE /Chez J. B. Patry Md. Libraire./ 1772. [and] DEDIÉ A/MESSIRE J. B. N. D. D'APRÉS DE BLANGY ECUYER SIEUR DE MANNEVILLETTE/Chevalier de l'Ordre du Roy, Capitaine des Vaisseaux de la Compagnie des Indes, Inspecteur pour le Roy,/et Garde du Dépôt des Cartes Plans et Journaux concernant la Navigation de l'Indé au Port de l'Orient,/Correspondant de l'Académie Royale des Sciences et Associé de l'Académie Royale de Marine &c./Par son trés humble et trés Obeissant Serviteur et Ami Dicquemare.
      Notes: Linen-backed. Uncolored. 39 x 36 3/8 inches, overall. 7 x 4 3/4 inches, folded.
    - IK 58 The Roads of the Province of Brittany. Ogée., 1771
      Map tab inscription: Bretagne/1771 [and] IK/58.
      Title and/or other information taken from map: Carte Itinéraire de la/Province de Bretagne/Dressé par le Sieur Ogée,/Ingénieur Géographe de la Province/Celle Carte se trouve à Nantes chès l'Auteur/Avec privilege du Roi 1771. [and] Bonnet Sculp. [and] Imprimé par J.B. Dutertre.
      Notes: Colored. 13 3/4 x 21 3/8 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 49, folder 777.
    - IK 52 The Province of Britanny, Paris: Jean B. Nolin., 1703
      Inscribed on map: IK/52. [and] bretagne
      Title and/or other information taken from map: LA/ PROVINCE ou DUCHE de/BRETAGNE/Divisée en deux Grandes Parties, qui sont/La HAUTE, et la BASSE BRETAGNE/Le Gouvernement General de BRETAGNE, Comprenant les/ LIEUTENANCES GENERALES de BRETAGNE/et du COMTÉ NANTOIS./La Lieutenance Generale de BRETAGNE est partagée en/ LIEUTENANCES de ROY de HAUTE et de BASSE BRETAGNE/qui sont subdivisées en plusieurs EVECHEZ./Dressée sur divers Memoires Nouveaux du Sr. Tillemon/et Dediée/A SON ALTESSE ROYALE MONSIEUR/FILS DE FRANCE, FRERE VNIQUE DU ROY, ET DUC D'ORLEANS./par son tres humble et tres obeissant serviteur Jean B. Nolin./A PARIS/Chez I. B. Nolin sur le Quay de l'Horloge du Palais, à l'Enseigne/de la Place des Victoires, Vers le Pont Neuf./Avec Privilege du Roy./1703.
      Notes: Uncolored. 19 1/16 x 25 5/8 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 49, folder 778.
    - IK 57 Brittany Divided in Nine Dioceses. Paris: Alexis Hubert Jaillot., 1706
      Map tab inscription: Bretagne/IK/57.
      Title and/or other information taken from map: LA BRETAGNE/DIVISEE EN SES NEUF EVESCHÉS/QUI FONT AUSSI L'ESTENDUE DES RECEPTES DE LA/GENERALITÉ DE NANTES./ DEDIÉE A MONSEIGNEUR/MONSEIGNEUR DE PONTCHARTRAIN/ Ministre Secretaire d'Estat/et Controlleur general des Finances./Par son tres-humble et tres-obeissa[n]t Serviteur/ HUBERT IAILLOT, Geographe du Roy. [and] A Paris, joignant les Grands Augustins, aux deux Globes,/Avec Privilége du Roy./1706 [and] Cordier, Sculpsit.
      Notes: Colored. 22 1/2 x 31 1/2 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 874.
    - IK 56 Map of the Roads of the Province of Brittany. Paris: P. R., 1778
      Map tab inscription: Bretagne/IK/56.
      Inscribed on map: 3 Cartes du Bretagne
      Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE/DES ROUTES/DE LA PROVINCE/DE BRETAGNE/De la Basse Normandie,/ Partie de l'Anjou du Poitou/le Pays d Aunis, et Saintonge;/ Par Mr. P. R...Ingenieur./1778/A Paris chez Le Clerc/Rue St. Martin.
      Notes: Colored. 27 13/16 x 20 7/8 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 49, folder 779.
    - IK 328 The Island of Guernsey. Bellin., 1757 (Box 11, Folder 364)
      Inscribed on map: IK/328. [and] illegible inscription
      Inscribed on label laid down on map: isle de grenezey. [and] A PARIS CHEZ JULIEN/A L'HOTEL DE SOUBISE
      Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE DE/ L'ISLE DE GRENESEY/Dressée au Depost des Cartes et Plans de la Marine/POUR LE SERVICE DES VAISSEAUX DU ROY/Par ordre de M. de Machault Garde des Sceaux de France/Ministre et Secretaire d'Etat aiant le Departt. de la Marine./M.DCC. LVII/...Par M. Bellin Ingenieur de la Marine et du Depost/ des Cartes et Plans &cCa/Tiré de Manuscrits Anglois nouvellement/acquis pour le Depost
      Notes: Linen-backed. Uncolored. 17 3/8 x 22 3/4 inches, overall. 7 5/8 x 5 7/8 inches, folded.
    - IK 329 The Island of Jersey. Bellin., 1755 (Box 11, Folder 365)
      Inscribed on map: IK/329
      Inscribed on label laid down on map: isle de Jersey
      Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE DE/ L'ISLE DE JERSEY./Dressée au Depost des Cartes et Plans de la Marine/POUR LE SERVICE DES VAISSEAUX DU ROY/Par ordre de M. de Machault Garde des Sceaux de France/Ministre et Secretaire d'Etat aiant le Departemt. de la Marine./M.DCC. LVII./...Tirée de la Carte Angloise du Cape. Clement Lempriere &a. a Londres/1755./Par M. Bellin Ingr. de la Marine et du Depost des/Cartes et Plans, &ca.
      Notes: Linen-backed. Uncolored. 17 1/4 x 22 3/4 inches, overall. 7 3/4 x 5 3/4 inches, folded.
    - IK 1 Map of Ireland. (Box 11, Folder 366-369)
      1) Map tab inscription on part 1: No. 1.
      Inscribed on map, part 1: illegible inscription
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 1: 1ere Partie de la carte d'Irland
      Inscribed on label attached to map, part 1: 1 K/non classée
      Title and/or other information taken from map, part 1: A MAPP/OF THE KINGDOM OF/IRELAND/NEWLY CORRECTED & IMPROV'D By Actual Observations/Divided into its PROVINCES COUNTIES & BARONIES And Supply'd with many/Market Towns & other Places of Note Omitted in former Mapps with all the Principal Roads & the Distances from Place/to Place in Comon Reputed Miles by Inspection And wherein the Citys & Chief Towns, Arch:Bishopricks, & Bishopricks/Burroughs, Market Towns, Villages & Barracks, are Respectively distinguish'd by different Characters and the/Lakes Bogs Mountains Rivers Bridges Ferryes & Passes described with several other Additions./Alterations and Amendments Together with Plans of the Citys and Fortified Towns As Allso a short/Description of the Kingdom By HENRY PRATT/To this map is added a large Index of the Measur'd Distances of ev'ry town from Dublin/of the Burroughs, Barracks, and Post Towns with Many other Improvements/and Emendations TABULA HIBERNIAE NOVIS [continued on part 2]
      Notes to map, part 1: This is the upper left quarter of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 25 1/8 x 20 3/4 inches, overall. 7 3/4 x 5 1/4 inches, folded. There is another copy of this map, also colored - see IK 336, part 1.
      2) Map tab inscription on part 2: No. 2.
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 2: 2eme. Partie de la Carte d'Irland
      Title and/or other information taken from map, part 2: [continued from Map, part I] SIMA ET EMENDATISSIMA
      Notes to map, part 2: This is the upper right quarter of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 25 1/8 x 20 5/16 inches, overall. 7 3/4 x 5 1/4 inches, folded. There is another copy of this map, also colored - see IK 336, part 2.
      3) Map tab inscription on part 3: No. 3.
      Inscribed on map, part 3: illegible inscription
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 3: 3eme. Partie de la Carte d'Irland
      Notes to map, part 3: This is the lower left quarter of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 25 1/4 x 20 3/4 inches, overall. 7 7/8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded. There is another copy of this map, also colored - see IK 336, part 3.
      4) Map tab inscription on part 4: No. 4
      Inscribed on map, part 4: illegible inscription
      Inscribed on label laid down on map: 4eme Partie de la Carte d'Irland
      Notes to map, part 4: This is the lower right quarter of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 25 1/4 x 20 3/4 inches, overall. 7 7/8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded. There is another copy of this map, also colored - see IK 336, part 4.
  - AMERICAN REVOLUTION
    - IK 361 Parts 1, 2, 3, & 4. North America by John Mitchell. Paris: Le Rouge., 1777 (Box 11, Folder 370-373)
      This map is divided into 8 parts. There are two copies of this map - one is another French edition, also colored - see IK 360, map no. 1; the other is an English edition, uncolored - see Unclassified map no. 2 in Series VII.
      1) Map tab, part 1: No inscription
      Inscribed on map, part 1: IK/361.
      Inscribed on label laid down on map, part 1: No. 1 Amerique Sept 1e/de Mitchel en 8. flles
      Notes to map, part 1: This is the upper left section (1/8th) of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 27 3/8 x 20 7/8 inches, overall. 7 7/8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
      2) Map tab, part 2: No inscription.
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 2: No. 2. Amérique
      Notes to map, part 2: This is the upper left center section (1/8th) of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 27 3/8 x 20 7/8 inches, overall. 8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
      3) Map tab, part 3: No inscription.
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 3: No. 3. Amérique
      Notes to map, part 3: This is the upper right center section (1/8th) of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 27 3/8 x 20 7/8 inches, overall. 8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
      4) Map tab, part 4: No inscription
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 4: No. 4 Amérique
      Notes to map, part 4: This is the upper right section (1/8th) of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 27 3/8 x 20 7/8 inches, overall. 8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
    - IK 361 Parts 5, 6, 7, & 8. North America by John Mitchell. Paris: Le Rouge., 1777 (Box 12, Folder 374-377)
      5) Map tab, part 5: No inscription
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 5: No. 5. Amérique
      Notes to map, part 5: This is the lower left section (1/8th) of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 28 x 20 7/8 inches, overall. 7 7/8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
      6) Map tab, part 6: No inscription
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 6: No. 6. Amérique
      Notes to map, part 6: This is the lower center left section (1/8th) of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 28 x 20 7/8 inches, overall. 7 7/8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
      7) Map tab, part 7: Inscription illegible
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 7: No. 7. Amérique
      Notes to map, part 7: This is the lower center right section (1/8th) of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 27 7/8 x 20 7/8 inches, overall. 7 7/8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
      8) Map tab, part 8: Inscription illegible.
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 8: No. 8. Amérique
      Title and/or other information taken from map, part 8: AMERIQUE/SEPTENTRIONALE/avec les Routes, Distances en miles, Villages et/ETABLISSEMENTS/François et Anglois/Par le Docteur Mitchel/Traduit de l'Anglois/A PARIS/Par le Rouge Ingr. Geographe du Roy rue des Grands Augustins 1777/ Corigée en 1776 par M. Hawkins Brigadier des armées du Roi. [and again similarly in German]. [and] Carte dresée par ordre de Messieurs les Commissaires/du Commerce, sur plusieurs Topographies Levées sur/les Lieux, que Mrs. les Gouverneurs des dittes Colonies/ont envoye a notre Bureau/ A Londres au Bureau des Colonies le 13 Fev: 1755./J [rest missing] --oional/--- etaire
      Notes to map, part 8: This is the lower right section (1/8th) of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 28 x 20 7/8 inches, overall. 7 7/8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
    - IK 362 Maps of the East Coast of North America
      - No. 1 Theater of War in America. Paris: Le Rouge., 1777 (Box 12, Folder 378)
        Map tab: No inscription
        Inscribed on map: IK/362
        Inscribed on label laid down on map: Amerique Septentrionale
        Title and/or other information taken from map: THEATRE DE LA GUERRE EN AMÉRIQUE Par le Sr. le Rouge Ingenieur Geographe du Roy. a Paris rue des Augustins. Avec Privilege du Roi 1777.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 25 1/2 x 20 7/8 inches, overall. 7 7/8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded. There is another copy of this map, also colored - see IK 370, No. 2.
      - No. 2 New Map of the Province of Québec by Captain Carver. Paris: Le Rouge., 1777 (Box 12, Folder 379)
        Inscribed on label laid down on map: Province de Quebec
        Title and/or other information taken from map: NOUVELLE CARTE/DE LA/PROVINCE DE QUEBEC/selon l'Edit du Roi d'Angleterre/du 7. 8bre. 1763/par le Capitaine Carver/et autres/Traduites de l'Anglois/A PARIS/Chez le Rouge/rue des grands Augustins/1777.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 20 15/16 x 27 11/16 inches, overall. 8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded. There are two copies of this map, also colored - see IK 395, map no. 2, and IK 360, map no. 9.
      - No. 3 Nova Scotia or the Eastern part of Canada. Paris: Le Rouge., [1775] (Box 12, Folder 380)
        Inscribed on label laid down on map: Nouvelle Ecosse
        Title and/or other information taken from map: Nouvelle Ecosse ou PARTIE ORIENTALE/DU CANADA/Traduitte de l'Anglois de la Carte de Jefferys publiée a Londres/en May 1755. A Paris par Le Rouge Ingenieur Geographe du Roy. Rue des Grands Augustins
        Notes: Linen-backed. Uncolored. 20 1/2 x 26 1/8 inches, overall. 7 7/8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded. There are two copies of this map, both colored - see IK 396, map no. 2; and IK 360, map no. 10. Map dated 1755, i.e. 1775.
      - No. 4 Bay of Delaware after Joshua Fisher. Paris: Le Rouge., 1777 (Box 12, Folder 381)
        Inscribed on label laid down on map: Baye de la Delaware
        Title and/or other information taken from map: BAYE/DE LA DELAWARE/Avec les Ports, Sondes,/Dangers, Bancs. &c./depuis les Caps Jusqu'a Philadelphie/d'Après la Carte/de Joshua Fisher/publiée a Philadelphie/A PARIS/ Chéz le Rouge rue des/grands Augustins./1777./Avec Privilége du Roi
        Notes: Linen-backed. Uncolored. 19 11/16 x 26 1/4 inches, overall. 8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded. There are two copies of this map, uncolored - see IK 371, map no. 4; and IK 360, map no. 12.
      - No. 5 New map of the Coasts of the Carolinas by Pocock. Paris: Le Rouge., 1777 (Box 12, Folder 382)
        Inscribed on label laid down on map: Côtes des environs de Charles town
        Title and/or other information taken from map: NOUVELLE CARTE DES COTES/DES CAROLINES/SEPTENTRIONALES ET MERIDIONALES/du Cap Fear a Sud Edisto/Levées et Sondées par N. Pocock en 1770./Traduites de l'Anglois./A PARIS/ Chez LE ROUGE rue/des Grands Augustins/1777.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Uncolored. 17 x 26 1/8 inches, overall. 7 7/8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded. There are two copies of this map, also uncolored - see IK 370, Map No. 3; and IK 360, map no. 8.
      - No. 6 Map of the Disturbances in America, by Claude Joseph Sauthier and Bernard Ratzer. Paris: Le Rouge., 1778 (Box 12, Folder 383)
        Inscribed on label laid down on map: Province de New-york et New jersey/depuis Quebec jusqu'au Cap hinlopen
        Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE DES TROUBLES DE/L'AMÉRIQUE/Levée par Ordre/DU CHEVALIER TRYON/Capitaine Général et Gouverneur/De la PROVINCE de/NEW-YORK/Ensemble la Province de/NEW-JERSEY/ Par SAUTHIER et RATZER/Traduit de l'Anglais/A PARIS/Chez Le Rouge Ingr. Geographe du Roi/Rue des Gds. Augustins. 1778. Beaublé Scripsit
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 31 1/4 x 21 7/8 inches, overall. 8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded. There are two copies of this map, also colored - see IK 371 map no. 1; and IK 360, map no. 6.
    - IK 372 South Carolina and Georgia. Paris: Le Rouge., 1777 (Box 12, Folder 384-387)
      This map is divided into 4 parts. There are two copies of this map - see IK 370, map no. 5, also an uncolored section, and IK 360, map no. 13, colored.
      1) South Carolina
      Map tab on map, part 1: No inscription
      Inscribed on map, part 1: IK/372.
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 1: No. 1. Caroline Meridionale/et Georgie en 4 flles.
      Notes to map, part 1: This is the upper left quarter of the map. Linen-backed. Uncolored. 31 3/8 x 21 3/4 inches, overall. 7 7/8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
      2) South Carolina and Georgia
      Map tab on map, part 2: Illegible inscription
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 2: No. 2 Caroline Meridionale/et Georgie
      Notes to map, part 2: This is the upper right quarter of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 31 3/8 x 21 3/4 inches, overall. 8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
      3) Southern Carolina and part of Georgia by William Bull and Captain Bryan, at Paris, Le Rouge
      Map tab on map, part 3: Illegible inscription
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 3: No. 3 Caroline Meridionale/et Georgie
      Title and/or other information taken from map, part 3: CAROLINE/MERIDIONALE/et Partie de la/GEORGIE/Par le Chevr. BULL Gouverneur Lieutenant./le Capitaine Gascoign. Chevr. BRYAN./et de Brahm Arpenteur Général de la Caroline Meridle./et un des Arpenteurs de la Georgie./en 4 Feuilles./A PARIS/Chez le Rouge Ingénieur Geographe du Roi./rue des grands Augustins/avec Privilege du Roi./1777.
      Notes to map, part 3: This is the lower left quarter of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 31 3/8 x 21 3/4 inches, overall. 7 7/8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
      4) The course of the Hudson River and connection with Canada by Sauthier, Le Rouge
      Map tab on map, part 4: Illegible inscriptio
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 4: No. 4 Caroline Meridionale/et Georgie
      Title and/or other information taken from map, part 4, for a small section of the overall map: COURS/DE LA RIVIERE D'HUDSON/et la Comunication avec/LE CANADA/Par le Lac Champlain/Jusqu'au Fort Chambly/par Sauthier/a 4 Miles pour pouce anglois/A PARIS/Chéz Le Rouge rue des/Grands Augustins/1777/Avec Privilége du Roi.
      Notes to map, part 4: This is the lower right quarter of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 31 3/8 x 21 3/4 inches, overall. 8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
    - IK 373 Parts 1 & 2. Virginia and Maryland by Fry and Jefferson. Paris: Le Rouge., 1777 (Box 13, Folder 388-389)
      This map is made up of 2 parts. There are two copies of this map, also colored - see IK 371, map no. 5, and IK 360 No. 7.
      1) Map tab on map, part 1: No inscription
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 1: No. 1. Virginie Maryland/en 2 flle [and] IK/373.
      Notes to map, part 1: This is the left half of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 28 x 20 3/4 inches, overall. 7 3/4 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
      2) No map tab on map, part 2
      Inscribed on label laid down on map 2: No. 2. Virginie Maryland
      Title and/or other information taken from map, part 2: VIRGINIE,/MARYLAND/en 2 feuilles/par Fry et Jefferson/ Traduit, Corrigé, augmenté/A PARIS/Chéz LE ROUGE Jng? Géographe du Roi/Rue des Grands Augustins/1777./Avec Privilége du Roi
      Notes to map, part 2: This is the right half of the map. Linen-backed. Colored. 27 3/4 x 20 1/2 inches, overall. 7 3/4 inches x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
    - IK 363 Maps of North America
      - No. 1. Map of North America Drawn by Order of Mr. de Sartine., 1778 (Box 13, Folder 390)
        Inscribed on map: IK/363
        Inscribed on label laid down on map: Cte. Réduitte de l'amérique/Septentrionnalle/Partie Meridionalle. [and] IK 363
        Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE RÉDUITE/DES COTES ORIENTALES/DE L'AMÉRIQUE SEPTENTRIONALE/CONTENANT/Partie du Nouveau Jersey, la Pen-sylvanie, le Mary-land, la Virginie,/la Caroline Septentrionale, la Caroline Méridionale et la Georgie,/ Assujettie aux Observations les plus récentes et aux Cartes de détail les plus estimées./Dressée au Dépôt Général des Cartes, Plans et Journaux de la Marine,/POUR LE SERVICE DES VAISSEAUX DU ROI./Par Ordre de M DE SARTINE, Conseiller d'Etat,/Ministre et Secretaire d'Etat, ayant le Département de la Marine./1778.
        Notes to map no. 1: Linen-backed. Uncolored. 23 x 34 3/4 inches, overall. 7 5/8 x 5 1/8 inches, folded. There is another copy of this map, colored - see no. 4.
      - No. 2. Newport., n.d. (Box 13, Folder 391)